{
  "title": "3.11",
  "definitions": {
    "TYRANT": {
      "word": "TYRANT",
      "phonetic": "(tl-rÔøΩnt)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a dictator, cruel ruler </p><p>A TYRANT is a person who seizes power in a country and then proceeds to rule in a very cruel and unfair way. A TYRANT is a <i class=“def-ital\">dictator</i>, a person whose word is law. </p><p>“The TYRANT grew wealthy by placing taxes on just about everything.” </p><p>“The people hated the TYRANT who ruled over them in such a cruel fashion.” </p><p>The word TYRANT is also used about any person who rules others unfairly. </p><p>“He thinks his mother is a TYRANT just because she won’t let him drive at night.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: TYRANNICAL, adj. TYRANNIZE, v. TYRANNY, n.</p>"
    },
    "RESIDE": {
      "word": "RESIDE",
      "phonetic": "(ri-zld')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to live, dwell </p><p>To RESIDE in a place is to live there, to have your home there. </p><p>“He RESIDES in Florida now.” </p><p>“She RESIDES in one state, but works in another.” </p><p>A RESIDENCE is a place where someone lives, a <i class=“def-ital\">home</i>, especially a large or dignified one. </p><p>“Their RESIDENCE is the brick house at the end of the street.” </p><p>It is also the act of RESIDING. </p><p>“After years of living in a house we took up RESIDENCE in an apartment.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: RESIDENCE, n. RESIDENTIAL, adj.</p>"
    },
    "IMMORTAL": {
      "word": "IMMORTAL",
      "phonetic": "(i-mort'-1)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">undying, deathless, lasting forever </p><p> The Latin word <i class=“def-ital\"><i class=“def-ital\">mors means death. It is the source of the words <i class=“def-ital\">mortal</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">mortality</i>. Someone or something that is IMMORTAL will not die, will last forever. The word is usually applied to people’s souls or to their actions and achievements. </p><p>“Patrick Henry said those IMMORTAL words, ‘Give me liberty or give me death!’” </p><p>“Everyone should read Shakespeare’s IMMORTAL plays.” </p><p>To IMMORTALIZE something is to make it last or be remembered forever. </p><p>“Longfellow’s poem IMMORTALIZED Paul Revere’s ride.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: IMMORTALITY, n. IMMORTALIZE, v.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">in-2</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-al</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "PACT": {
      "word": "PACT",
      "phonetic": "(pakt)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an agreement, compact </p><p>A PACT is an agreement between persons or groups. </p><p>“We made a PACT that neither of us would tell the secret.” </p><p>PACT is often used when referring to agreements or treaties between countries. </p><p>“The two nations signed a PACT that each would help the other in time of war.” </p><p>“The PACT limited the size of each nation’s army.”</p>"
    },
    "RECOIL": {
      "word": "RECOIL",
      "phonetic": "(ri-koyl')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to draw back, move backward, shrink </p><p> To RECOIL is to draw back or jump back, especially because of fear, horror, or disgust. </p><p>“I RECOILED when he offered to let me hold the spider.” </p><p>RECOIL does not always suggest an actual physical movement. You can RECOIL inwardly from something as well. </p><p>“They RECOILED in horror from the idea of visiting the haunted house.” </p><p>RECOIL is also used with regard to a gun kicking back when it is fired. </p><p>“He steadied himself so that he wouldn’t be knocked over when the rifle RECOILED.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">re-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "INFLICT": {
      "word": "INFLICT",
      "phonetic": "(in-flikt')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to lay on, impose </p><p>To INFLICT something is to cause it to be suffered. You always INFLICT something unpleasant or painful, like damage or physical punishment. </p><p>“The bomb INFLICTED serious damage on the city.” </p><p>“The bully INFLICTED a terrible beating on him.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: INFLICTION, n. </p><p>Usage: INFLICT is usually used with <i class=“def-ital\">on</i>: to INFLICT something on someone.</p>"
    },
    "INTENTION": {
      "word": "INTENTION",
      "phonetic": "(in-ten'-shÔøΩn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">purpose, aim </p><p>INTEND means “to have in mind as something to be done.” </p><p>“I INTEND to go to the beach this summer.” </p><p>An INTENTION is something that you have in mind that you want to do, a <i class=“def-ital\">purpose</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">goal</i>. </p><p>“I have no INTENTION of watching television tonight.” </p><p>“His INTENTIONS were good, but he didn’t carry them out.” </p><p>“She announced her INTENTION to run for mayor in the next election.” </p><p>Many people think an INTENTION is a <i class=“def-ital\">wish</i>. The words are close in meaning, but INTENTION suggests a much stronger determination to do something. Anyone can wish to be famous, for example; but if it is your INTENTION, you are going to work hard to see that it happens. </p><p>Other forms of the word: INTEND, v. INTENTIONAL, adj.</p>"
    },
    "OBLIGATION": {
      "word": "OBLIGATION",
      "phonetic": "(ob-lÔøΩgA'-shÔøΩn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a duty, responsibility </p><p>An OBLIGATION is something that you must do (or not do). It is a duty that results from a law, a custom, a promise, or the like. </p><p>“He felt he had an OBLIGATION to help those less fortunate than he was.” </p><p>“You have an OBLIGATION to pay back the money I lent you.” </p><p>“He carried out his OBLIGATION to the company, and then felt he didn’t have to do anything more.” </p><p>“There is no OBLIGATION to buy anything. We just want you to try our product for ten days.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: OBLIGE, v.</p>"
    },
    "PORTRAY": {
      "word": "PORTRAY",
      "phonetic": "(por-trA')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to picture, describe, represent </p><p>To PORTRAY means “to make a picture of” someone or something. You can PORTRAY by painting. </p><p>“He PORTRAYED the queen as a beautiful young woman in the painting.” </p><p>Or you can PORTRAY in words. </p><p>“The king is PORTRAYED as a villain in this novel.” </p><p>Actors PORTRAY characters on stage; that is, they present a picture of the characters. </p><p>“She PORTRAYED Hamlet’s mother in the play.” </p><p>A PORTRAIT is a picture, particularly a painting of a person. </p><p>“Whistler painted a famous PORTRAIT of his mother.” </p><p>The most commonly chosen wrong answer in the Pretest item is <i class=“def-ital\">deceive</i>, probably because of confusion with <i class=“def-ital\">betray</i>. </p><p>Other forms of the word: PORTRAIT, n.</p>"
    },
    "STATIONARY": {
      "word": "STATIONARY",
      "phonetic": "(stA'-shÔøΩner-E)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">unmoving, fixed in position </p><p>STATIONARY is related to the word STATION. Both come from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">stand</i>. One meaning of STATION is “a place where something or someone stands.” </p><p>“A guard should never leave his STATION.” </p><p>Something that is STATIONARY stands in one place; it cannot or does not move. </p><p>“Nothing was moving on the whole street. All the cars were STATIONARY.” </p><p>“These heavy machines are STATIONARY; once they are set in place they can’t be moved.”</p>"
    },
    "RENOVATE": {
      "word": "RENOVATE",
      "phonetic": "(ren'-ÔøΩvAt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to restore, renew, revive </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">nov</i> part of the word comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">new</i>, also the source of the words <i class=“def-ital\">novel</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">novelty</i>. To RENOVATE something is to make it new again. The word is usually applied to the restoring and repairing of old buildings so that they are like new again. </p><p>“We would like to RENOVATE our apartment. We want to fix it up completely.” </p><p>“The kitchen was old-fashioned and had to be RENOVATED before they could sell the house.” </p><p>Many people think RENOVATE means <i class=“def-ital\">tear down</i>, which means just about the opposite. </p><p>Other forms of the word: RENOVATION, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">re-</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ate1</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "SKETCHY": {
      "word": "SKETCHY",
      "phonetic": "(skech'-E)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">incomplete, like a SKETCH, without details </p><p>A SKETCH is an outline of something, a quick drawing, not the complete picture. Anything that is SKETCHY is like a SKETCH. It is incomplete, lacking in detail.  The word is used especially about understanding or information that is only vague and incomplete. </p><p>“Her understanding of algebra is somewhat SKETCHY.” </p><p>“He could only give us SKETCHY directions on how to get there.” </p><p>“We had only a SKETCHY idea of what the movie was supposed to be about.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SKETCH, n., v.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-y</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "TOPPLE": {
      "word": "TOPPLE",
      "phonetic": "(top'-ÔøΩI)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to fall, fall over; to push over, overturn </p><p>To TOPPLE is to <i class=“def-ital\">fall over</i>, especially from being too heavy on top. </p><p>“He piled the bricks so high that the stack TOPPLED.” </p><p>“The strong winds finally caused the tree to TOPPLE with a crash.” </p><p>To TOPPLE something is to push it over or overturn it. </p><p>“The mean boys TOPPLED the snowman we had just finished.” </p><p>The word is often used about the overthrowing of someone in a position of authority. </p><p>“The rebels TOPPLED the dictator’s government.”</p>"
    },
    "YEARN": {
      "word": "YEARN",
      "phonetic": "(yern)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to long, pine </p><p>To YEARN for something is to desire it strongly, usually with an eager or tender kind of feeling. </p><p>“He YEARNED for one last chance to see his native land.” </p><p>“Billy YEARNED to be a famous baseball player.” </p><p>“The prisoner YEARNED to be free.” </p><p>YEARNING is the noun from YEARN. A YEARNING is a longing or a strong desire. </p><p>“She felt a deep YEARNING to help humanity.” </p><p>“He never satisfied his YEARNING for more money.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: YEARNING, n.</p>"
    },
    "DRAB": {
      "word": "DRAB",
      "phonetic": "(drab)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">dull, monotonous, uninteresting, colorless </p><p>Something that is DRAB is uninteresting, colorless, lifeless. </p><p>“His wife’s lovely personality lent color to his otherwise DRAB existence.” </p><p>The word DRAB is also used in a more specific sense to describe a dull, muddy brown or gray color. </p><p>“The DRAB color scheme of the room made it lifeless and uninviting.” </p><p>Many people think DRAB means <i class=“def-ital\">filthy</i>. Something may be colorless and dull, however, and still be perfectly clean.</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "11",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He is the TYRANT.",
          "answers": [
            "dictator",
            "priest",
            "newcomer",
            "president",
            "teacher"
          ],
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "dictator"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Where do they RESIDE?",
          "answers": [
            "meet",
            "work",
            "perform",
            "live",
            "travel"
          ],
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "live"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMMORTAL fame.",
          "answers": [
            "brief",
            "undying",
            "human",
            "general",
            "great"
          ],
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "undying"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Understood the PACT.",
          "answers": [
            "crowd",
            "argument",
            "result",
            "agreement",
            "article"
          ],
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "agreement"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To RECOIL suddenly.",
          "answers": [
            "draw back",
            "give up",
            "attack",
            "fall down",
            "turn"
          ],
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "draw back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFLICT the punishment.",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "lay on",
            "escape",
            "accept",
            "ask for"
          ],
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "lay on"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Understood his INTENTION.",
          "answers": [
            "wish",
            "opposition",
            "nervousness",
            "demand",
            "purpose"
          ],
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "purpose"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Clear OBLIGATION.",
          "answers": [
            "right",
            "duty",
            "statement",
            "opportunity",
            "command"
          ],
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "duty"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To PORTRAY him.",
          "answers": [
            "deceive",
            "forget",
            "picture",
            "meet",
            "talk to"
          ],
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "picture"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STATIONARY vehicles.",
          "answers": [
            "official",
            "speedy",
            "unmoving",
            "temporary",
            "broken"
          ],
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "unmoving"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RENOVATE the building.",
          "answers": [
            "clean",
            "tear down",
            "sell",
            "leave",
            "restore"
          ],
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "restore"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SKETCHY knowledge.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "growing",
            "incomplete",
            "forgotten",
            "misleading"
          ],
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "incomplete"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They TOPPLED the statue.",
          "answers": [
            "pushed over",
            "set up",
            "finished",
            "marked",
            "destroyed"
          ],
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "pushed over"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To YEARN for it.",
          "answers": [
            "work",
            "wait",
            "plan",
            "long",
            "come"
          ],
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "long"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DRAB rugs.",
          "answers": [
            "colorless",
            "tom",
            "striped",
            "bright",
            "filthy"
          ],
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "colorless"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is a TYRANT cruel?",
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people often RESIDE in factories?",
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are you IMMORTAL?",
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can countries make PACTS with one another?",
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you like something that makes you RECOIL?",
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it possible to INFLICT damage on a car if you hit it with a hammer?",
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does an INTENTION have to do with the future?",
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do parents have an OBLIGATION to care for their children?",
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you PORTRAY a person in a story?",
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a jet STATIONARY when it is in the air?",
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a brand new building have been RENOVATED?",
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people want to go to a doctor who has a SKETCHY knowledge of medicine?",
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be difficult to TOPPLE a mountain?",
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people YEARN for happiness?",
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are rainbows DRAB?",
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "At work he was mild and kind, but at home he was an unjust TYRANT to his children.",
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After living in a cottage all summer, he returned to his permanent RESIDENCE.",
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Mona Lisa was IMMORTALIZED in Leonardo Da Vinci's painting.",
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The heavy PACT was almost impossible to carry.",
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He RECOILED at the thought of eating raw oysters.",
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I have never been so INFLICTED in my life as when I heard that we had won the lottery.",
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I INTEND to go to Europe some day, no matter how much it costs.",
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I have no OBLIGATION to help you do your homework.",
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The actor PORTRAYED a character who loved money more than anything else.",
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We bolted the wobbly table to the wall so that it would remain STATIONARY.",
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The landlord called in a wrecking crew to RENOVATE the building.",
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her SKETCHY voice was very unpleasant to listen to.",
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The ice cream was TOPPLED with a chocolate sauce.",
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Mrs. Jones YEARNED to see her children.",
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She bought new curtains to brighten up the DRAB room.",
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "TYRANT",
          "answers": [
            "dictator",
            "soldier",
            "oppressor"
          ],
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESIDE",
          "answers": [
            "sleep",
            "live",
            "dwell"
          ],
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMMORTAL",
          "answers": [
            "endless",
            "deathless",
            "useless"
          ],
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PACT",
          "answers": [
            "agreement",
            "refusal",
            "treaty"
          ],
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOIL",
          "answers": [
            "shove",
            "shrink",
            "flinch"
          ],
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFLICT",
          "answers": [
            "harm",
            "tighten",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTENTION",
          "answers": [
            "goal",
            "aim",
            "need"
          ],
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBLIGATION",
          "answers": [
            "must",
            "duty",
            "choice"
          ],
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PORTRAY",
          "answers": [
            "paint",
            "describe",
            "hear"
          ],
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STATIONARY",
          "answers": [
            "standing",
            "unattached",
            "motionless"
          ],
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RENOVATE",
          "answers": [
            "relieve",
            "repair",
            "rebuild"
          ],
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SKETCHY",
          "answers": [
            "vague",
            "imperfect",
            "ancient"
          ],
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TOPPLE",
          "answers": [
            "push",
            "climb",
            "fall"
          ],
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "YEARN",
          "answers": [
            "hope",
            "expect",
            "desire"
          ],
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DRAB",
          "answers": [
            "old",
            "gray",
            "dull"
          ],
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}